# **Michael Jung**

# Software Engineer

■ themikejung@gmail.com 
mhtjung.github.io 
github.com/mhtjung in linkedin.com/in/themikejjung

#### **Profile**

I'm a software engineer in the San Diego, CA area with multiple years of experience in technologies including Go, JavaScript, Ruby, React, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, & Git/GitHub. I've deployed projects to AWS, Digital Ocean, and Heroku. Most recently, I designed and created Triage, a service for Kafka consumers that solves head-of-line blocking.

#### **Experience**

#### 2022 - present

## Co-Creator, Software Engineer

Triage (team-triage.github.io) □

Triage is an open-source consumer proxy for Apache Kafka that solves head-of-line blocking. Head-of-line blocking exists in queue-like structures and can cause crash/restart cycles, slow consumption of messages, and increased consumer lag, ultimately denigrating system performance. Triage enables parallel consumption of a single Kafka partition, greatly mitigating if not curing these negative effects altogether.

- Built Triage ☑ using Go, gRPC, Docker, and AWS
- Enabled parallel consumption of a single Kafka partition via concurrency in Go
- Resolved consumer delay and crash/restart cycles
- Resolved consumption latency caused by slow external services
- Constructed a deployment command line interface, distributed as an NPM package (triage-cli ☑)
- Implemented Triage's consumer client library in Go (triage-client-go ☑)
- Utilized gRPC for network communication, increasing message throughput and reducing network usage.
- Played a key role in the planning and implementation of Triage's application logic
- Collaborated with a fully remote team of engineers on a daily basis
- Authored technical case study for Triage, specifically design challenges and implementation sections

#### 2021 - 2022

### Software Engineer, Open Source

Built open source projects using Node.js, Vanilla JavaScript, Ruby, React, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

- Request Djinn An HTTP webhook inspector built using the MERN stack & PostgreSQL
- Notes A browser based note taking application build using the MERN stack
- Contacts Manager A simple light CRM for managing contacts built using the MVC pattern with Node.js, Express, and Handlebars

#### 2017 - 2019

#### **Account Executive**

HIPAA Vault

- Managed the sales lifecycle for clients in the cloud healthcare space, closing over \$1MM in ARR
- Worked hand in hand with technical staff to create a smooth customer onboarding for high priority clients

#### **Skills**

#### Languages & Frameworks

Go, Node.js, Vanilla JavaScript, React, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, SQL

# Tools

Apache Kafka, Docker/Dockerhub, Git/Github, HTTP, gRPC, NPM

#### **Platforms**

AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Linux, Windows (WSL 2)

#### **Education**

#### **Business Management**

Western Governor's University

#### **Business Management**

United States Air Force Academy